<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<wpiedata>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[29]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[Pensions Ombudsman's Office]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>The Government decided in 2013 to amalgamate the Office of the Pensions Ombudsman with the Financial Services Ombudsman Bureau. &nbsp;Work is on-going to bring this amalgamation about.</p>



<p>In preparation for this, the Office of the Pensions Ombudsman has recently moved to shared accommodation with the Financial Services Ombudsman Bureau.</p>



<p><strong>The new contact details are:</strong></p>



<p>Office of the Pensions Ombudsman,</p>



<p>4th Floor, Lincoln House,</p>



<p>Lincoln Place, Dublin 2.</p>



<p>Ph: &nbsp;+353 1 6766002 &nbsp; Fax: &nbsp;+353 1 6618776</p>



<p>Email: info@pensionsombudsman.ie</p>



<p>Website: <a href="http://www.pensionsombudsman.ie" target="_blank">www.pensionsombudsman.ie</a></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2015-09-15]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle><![CDATA[IIPM News - Pensions Ombudsman's Office]]></metatitle>
    <metadescription><![CDATA[IIPM News - Pensions Ombudsman's Office. The Government decided in 2013 to amalgamate the Office of the Pensions Ombudsman with the Financial Services Ombudsman Bureau.]]></metadescription>
    <metakeywords><![CDATA[Pensions Ombudsman's Office. The Government decided in 2013 to amalgamate the Office of the Pensions Ombudsman with the Financial Services Ombudsman Bureau]]></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[9]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[Pensions Authority Consultation on Trustee Qualifications]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>On 1st September 2015 The Pensions Authority issued a consultation document on trustee qualifications. Submissions can be made until 1st October 2015 and we will be responding to this on behalf of our members.</p>



<p>The consultation paper can be accessed by <a href="/resources/files/Trustee Qualifications.pdf">clicking here</a>.</p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2015-08-27]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title><![CDATA[News image]]></image_title>
    <metatitle><![CDATA[IIPM News - Pensions Authority consultation on trustee qualifications]]></metatitle>
    <metadescription><![CDATA[IIPM News - Pensions Authority consultation on trustee qualifications. On 1st September 2015 The Pensions Authority issued a consultation document on trustee qualifications. Submissions can be made until 1st October 2015 and we will be responding to this on behalf of our members.]]></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[28]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[Universal Retirement Savings System – Consultation and Invitation for Submissions]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>The Government has decided to proceed with work to develop a roadmap and timeline for the introduction of a new Universal Supplementary Workplace Retirement Savings Scheme.</p>



<p>Preparation of this roadmap for consideration by Government has been initiated through the establishment of a Universal Retirement Savings Group (USRG) chaired by the Department of Social Protection.</p>



<p>In order to facilitate input from the various sectoral interests and utilise the range of existing expertise, the USRG undertook a broad consultation exercise in April/May of this year and as part of the first stage of that process the IIPM was invited to make a submission on behalf of our members.</p>



<p>Please <a href="/resources/files/IIPM submission to URSG, Final.pdf">click here</a> to access our response to the consultation.</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2015-09-10]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle><![CDATA[IIPM News - Universal Retirement Savings System – consultation and invitation for submissions]]></metatitle>
    <metadescription><![CDATA[IIPM News - Universal Retirement Savings System – consultation and invitation for submissions. The Government has decided to proceed with work to develop a roadmap and timeline for the introduction of a new Universal Supplementary Workplace Retirement Savings Scheme. Preparation of this roadmap for consideration by Government has been initiated through the establishment of a Universal Retirement Savings Group (USRG) chaired by the Department of Social Protection. ]]></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[36]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[Tanaiste and Minister for Social Protection Secures Government Approval for Waterford Crystal Pension Settlement]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>The Taniste and Minister for SocialProtection, Joan Burton,T.D., secured Government approval on 9 December 2014 for a mediator set of recommendations to settle the long-running Waterford Crystal pensions case.</p>



<p><a href="http://www.merrionstreet.ie/en/News-Room/Releases/T%C3%A1naiste_and_Minister_for_Social_Protection_Secures_Government_Approval_for_Waterford_Crystal_Pension_Settlement.html#sthash.laQXX4tC.dpuf">http://www.merrionstreet.ie/en/News-Room/Release/T%C3%A1naiste_and_Minister_for_Social_Protection_Secures_Government_Approval_for_Waterford_Crystal_Pension_Settlement.html#sthash</a>.laQXX4tC.dpuf</p>



<p><br />

&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2015-11-13]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[34]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[IIPM Benefits & Salary Survey]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>In recent months Council of IIPM has put a renewed focus on communicating with external stakeholders to raise awareness of the industry and the value of IIPM qualifications. This work has included a redesign of the Institute&rsquo;s website and undertaking a survey of members to establish salary and benefits enjoyed by those who are part of the Institute.<br />

&nbsp;<br />

As with so many initiatives there was a high level of engagement from members who responded in great numbers to the salary survey. There was also significant interest in the results which were presented at a recent members&rsquo; seminar by Stephen O&rsquo;Hanlon and a representative of The Reputations Agency who conducted the survey independently on behalf of the Institute. Given the interest among members&nbsp;we wanted to share the results and the presentation for those who weren&rsquo;t able to join us that evening.</p>



<p><a href="file://staff-filesvr/caps$/IIPM/Events/Lectures/22.10.15/IIPM%20Salary%20&amp;%20Benefits%20Survey.pdf">Click here</a>&nbsp;to see the the survey results and findings.</p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2015-11-13]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[38]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[IIPM Submission to the Pensions Authority on Trustee Qualifications]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>The submission document&nbsp;can be accessed by clicking <a href="http://www.iipm.ie/resources/files/IIPM%20Submission%20to%20the%20PA%20on%20Trustee%20Qualifications%20092015%20IIPM%20and%20NCI.pdf">here</a></p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2016-01-12]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle><![CDATA[Trustee Qualifications]]></metatitle>
    <metadescription><![CDATA[IIPM Submission to the Pensions Authority on Trustee Qualifications]]></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[40]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[The "Omega Pharma" Case Summary]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>The decision of the High Court in the Omega Pharma case must be considered by trustees and employers dealing with the wind-up of a defined benefit scheme.&nbsp; Click on the link below for a full summary of the case.</p>



<p><a href="http://www.aonportal.ie/consulting/attachments/spotlight_issue53.pdf">http://www.aonportal.ie/consulting/attachments/spotlight_issue53.pdf</a></p>



<p><strong>The &quot;Omega Pharma&quot; case &ndash; upheld by Court of Appeal</strong></p>



<p>The decision of the High Court in the Omega Pharma case&nbsp;was appealed by the company, and at the Court of Appeal hearing in November 2014, the appeal was dismissed.&nbsp; The written judgment which was issued on 10 February 2015 addresses the two grounds of appeal:</p>



<ul>

<li>The Scheme documentation should have been interpreted as requiring the Scheme to be wound-up at the start of the notice and hence the contribution demand was invalid: the Court of Appeal decided that the documents should be read as providing for the wind-up to take place at the end of the notice period (in any event the employer had given three months&#39; notice in the letter of termination)</li>

<li>The correct measure of any shortfall on wind-up was the statutory minimum funding standard (MFS), and as the Scheme satisfied this, no further contribution was required: the Court of Appeal rejected this view as the rules required that the Trustees should have sufficient funds to provide the benefits under the Scheme.

<p>Hence the High Court decision that the employer was liable to pay the contribution demanded by the Trustees, even though the Scheme met the MFS, was upheld. Whilst this decision reflects the circumstances of this case, and the provisions of the Scheme rules, it reinforces the need for Trustees of a DB scheme which is being wound-up to consider what powers they have under the scheme documents to seek additional funding, and to take legal and actuarial advice.</p>

</li>

</ul>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2016-01-21]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[42]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[Pension investment manager choice - can unions have a role to play?]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p><em><strong>The following is taken from Industrial Relations news analysis in September 2015 by Coleman Higgins.</strong></em></p>



<p>The difficulties that have arisen over the choice of investment advisors/funds in the new pension schemes at Aer Lingus and Daa arise from a novel attempt to involve trade unions in the pension investment management selection process.</p>



<p>Trade unions have always been involved in negotiating pension contribution rates and benefits and, with the defined benefit (DB) pension crisis of recent years, also reductions in benefits and transfer terms to new defined contribution (DC) schemes.</p>



<p>However, once employees&#39; and employers&#39; money has gone into the pension scheme, decisions on how it is invested have traditionally been left to the trustees and the pensions industry, who try to get the best return for the scheme&#39;s members.</p>



<p>Several years ago, SIPTU&#39;s aviation pensions committtee, dissatistfied with the investment performance of the old IASS scheme shared between Aer Lingus and Daa, began to develop a Perfect Pension Partners Programme (PPPP), to select ideal invetsment managers for new planned DC schemes in both companies.</p>



<p>This consisted of meetings with a wide variety of pension providers, looking at their long-term performance, from which two investment managers were selected - Standard Life and Merrion Investment Managers.</p>



<p><strong>Two &quot;Pension Partners&quot;</strong></p>



<p>Since the trustee boards of both schemes were established earlier this year, SIPTU nominees on the boards have been argusing that these &quot;pension partners&quot; be considered for the shortlist.</p>



<p>The chairpersons of both boards have taken the traditional approach of selecting an investment advisor first, who looks at the needs of the individual scheme and comes up with a shortlist of potential investment managers.&nbsp; The ultimate decision as to which manager to use is for the trustees, with the assistance of the investment advisors.</p>



<p>SIPTU&#39;s pensions committee is understood not to be against the use of investment advisors to select an investment fund in this way, but is seeking more transparency for trustees in terms of how the scorinng system for selecting shortlists operates.&nbsp; Also, while tradionally the investment advisor was always totally separate to the investment fund, in recent years some firms have been offering both services.&nbsp; This has given rise to some concerns on the union side, which may or may not be justified.</p>



<p><strong>Professional Advise</strong></p>



<p>There is an obligation on trustees, if they are not themselves professional pension advisors, to obtain professional advice in the execution of their duties.</p>



<p>The Element Six pension judgement in 2014, although it involved a different type of trustee decision than choosing an investment advisor, made it clear that taking professional advice helped to protect trustees from legal action by scheme members that may later by unhappy with the result of their decisions.</p>



<p>SIPTU&#39;s pensions committee has participated in many training events and seminars, building up a signifcant expertise.&nbsp; While this may still not be seen as equivalent to the training received by those working in the pensions industry, it has meant a significantly greater engagement in pension issues, not just by the trustees, but also by other members of the union in terms of their awareness of how well their fund is doing.</p>



<p>The Pensions Authority, in a recent consultation paper on DC pension schemes, has called for significantly more education of trustees - a sentiment that the union side in the current row would agree with.</p>



<p><strong>Duty to All</strong></p>



<p>What may require more clarification is what level of involvement the union can have in relation to its nominated trustees.&nbsp; Even though the trustees are nominated by the union side, they have a legal duty as directors of the trustee company running the scheme to have regard to the interests of all members - which includes not just active members, by also deferred and retired members.</p>



<p>Few would have difficulty with a union providing advice and training to its members who are trustees.&nbsp; But the trustees still have to operate independently.&nbsp; The questionn here is whether arguing to include on a shortlist investment funds that performed well in a union research project could be seen as somehow compromising that independence.&nbsp; If those funds are indeed high performers, then all members benefit anyway.</p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2016-01-21]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[44]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[High Court Refuses to Look Behind Pensions Ombudsman Ruling]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>The document can be accessed by clicking this link: <a href="http://www.williamfry.com/newsandinsights/publications-article/2016/01/21/high-court-refuses-to-look-behind-pensions-ombudsman-ruling">http://www.williamfry.com/newsandinsights/publications-article/2016/01/21/high-court-refuses-to-look-behind-pensions-ombudsman-ruling</a></p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2016-01-22]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[46]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[Trustees Can Consider Employer's Interests]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>This document can be accessed by clicking the following link:<a href="http://www.williamfry.com/newsandinsights/publications-article/2016/01/21/trustees-can-consider-employer-s-interests">http://www.williamfry.com/newsandinsights/publications-article/2016/01/21/trustees-can-consider-employer-s-interests</a></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2016-01-22]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[48]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[Six things every woman needs to know about the State pension]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>The article can be accessed through the following link: <a href="http://www.irishtimes.com/business/personal-finance/six-things-every-woman-needs-to-know-about-the-state-pension-1.2448981">http://www.irishtimes.com/business/personal-finance/six-things-every-woman-needs-to-know-about-the-state-pension-1.2448981</a></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2016-01-28]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[media]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[50]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[Irish Institute of Pensions Management (IIPM) spearheads programme to upskill lay pension trustees]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p><strong>New initiative will support increased consumer protection in &euro;100 billion industry</strong></p>



<p>The Institute of Pensions Management (IIPM), has undertaken a major initiative to facilitate upskilling of lay pension trustees, many of whom act in a voluntary capacity, who are part of the oversight process of some 61,000 pension schemes nationwide. While the pension industry is heavily regulated, there is currently no requirement for the 180,000 lay trustees in Ireland to hold a relevant pensions management qualification in an industry which has approximately &euro;100 billion of assets under management on behalf of 400,000 scheme members.</p>



<p>The IIPM believes to truly serve pension scheme members trustees must understand the broad range of complex issues such as legal, actuarial, tax, investment, governance and risk management. Through appropriate upskilling these trustees will be better placed to challenge, assess and manage schemes more effectively. In order to develop the appropriate skills required to achieve this the IIPM has established the <em>&lsquo;IIPM Law and Governance Programme for Truste</em>es&rsquo;:- a programme of professional accreditation for lay trustees developed in association with National College of Ireland. Details of the new programme will be announced this week at the IIPM conference <em>Empowering Trustees for Better Member Outcomes, </em>with speakers from Ireland and the UK.</p>



<p>Ahead of the announcement, the prospectus for the IIPM Law and Governance Programme for Trustees was presented to the T&aacute;naiste and Minister for Social Protection, Joan Burton T.D., who welcomed the initiative to provide a certified qualification for lay pension trustees.</p>



<p><strong>Speaking about the initiative, Rose Leonard, President of the Irish Institute of Pension Management said:</strong> <em>&ldquo;</em><em>With assets under management of approximately &euro;100 billion, Irish pension schemes play a central role in Ireland&rsquo;s economic and social life. We are fortunate that by far the majority of trustees, who are either employer nominated or member elected, act with integrity and independence in the best interests of pension scheme members. However, given the scale of the industry and the crucial importance pension funds play in providing income for retirees there is a consumer protection imperative to ensure that those acting in an important oversight role have the necessary skills to perform their role as trustees. There are similar parallels to be drawn with the focus </em><em>in recent years on upskilling non-executive Directors who play a key oversight role in corporate governance. Upskilling of lay trustees can only serve to improve governance in the pensions industry and help maintain the highest standards for members, while creating further confidence within the sector.&rdquo;</em></p>



<p><strong>Commenting on the introduction of the IIPM&rsquo;s new professional programme, Brendan Kennedy, Pension Regulator, Pensions Authority said:</strong> <em>&ldquo;Improving trustee standards of education is an important part of the Pensions Authority&rsquo;s objectives. We therefore welcome the introduction of the &lsquo;IIPM Law and Governance Programme for Trustees&rsquo; as a very positive step in this direction and we hope that many trustees take advantage of this opportunity to enhance and develop their knowledge and understanding of pensions in the interests of the members whom they serve.&rdquo;</em></p>



<p><strong>The Pensions Ombudsman, Paul Kenny added:</strong> <em>&ldquo;I am very pleased to learn about the forthcoming launch of the &lsquo;IIPM Law and Governance Programme for Trustees&rsquo;. The pension environment is increasingly complex and the burden of regulation increasingly heavy. I believe that this programme will be a valuable support, particularly for lay trustees, whether member-selected or employer-appointed, which will enable them to continue to play an active role in the governance of their schemes, by broadening their understanding of the many and varied aspects of their duties and responsibilities.&rdquo;</em></p>



<p>Full details of the &lsquo;IIPM Law and Governance Programme for Trustees&rsquo; are available on <a href="file:///

epfs01filesDataCLIENTSIrish%20Institute%20of%20Pensions%20ManagementTrusteeship%20white%20paperwww.iipm.ie">www.iipm.ie</a></p>



<p><strong>About the qualification </strong></p>



<p><strong>The IIPM Law and Governance Qualification for Trustees</strong>.</p>



<p>The qualification offers trustees the insights and understanding required to carry out their roles effectively. Touching on the many aspects of pension schemes, the programme will focus on the building blocks for implementing good scheme governance and risk management.</p>



<p>The programme covers the core areas of trustees responsibilities imposed by both legislation and social needs and it examines the liabilities they face, compliance issues and the need for proper risk management. Trustees will have a deeper understanding of how risks can be mitigated through the implementation of good practices and procedures. Issues will be examined for both ongoing schemes and those in the process of wind-up.</p>



<p>Download Programme (click on image below):</p>



<p><a href="/resources/files/2016/IIPM%20Law%20and%20Governance%20Programme%20for%20Trustees.pdf" target="_blank"><img alt="" src="/resources/images/trustees.png" style="border-style:solid; border-width:0px; float:left; height:200px; margin:5px 10px; width:142px" /></a></p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2016-02-02]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[no]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image><![CDATA[D18136-0049 Rose with An Tánaiste and Regulator.jpg]]></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle><![CDATA[Irish Institute of Pensions Management (IIPM) spearheads programme to upskill lay pension trustees]]></metatitle>
    <metadescription><![CDATA[The Institute of Pensions Management (IIPM), has undertaken a major initiative to facilitate upskilling of lay pension trustees, many of whom act in a voluntary capacity, who are part of the oversight process of some 61,000 pension schemes nationwide]]></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[52]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[World's largest pension funds urge mining giants to increase transparency on climate change]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>This arcticle can be accessed by clicking on the following link: <a href="http://www.europeanpensions.net/ep/worlds-largest-pension-funds-urge-mining-giants-to-increase-transparency-on-climate-change.php">http://www.europeanpensions.net/ep/worlds-largest-pension-funds-urge-mining-giants-to-increase-transparency-on-climate-change.php</a></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2016-02-02]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[media]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[53]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[Going Dutch: Problems Concerning Increasing the State Pension Age?]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>This article can be accessed by clicking on the following link:</p>



<p><a href="http://www.mhc.ie/latest/insights/going-dutch-problems-concerning-increasing-the-state-pension-age?utm_source=Newsweaver&amp;utm_medium=Newsweaver&amp;utm_campaign=Newsweaver">http://www.mhc.ie/latest/insights/going-dutch-problems-concerning-increasing-the-state-pension-age?utm_source=Newsweaver&amp;utm_medium=Newsweaver&amp;utm_campaign=Newsweaver</a></p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2016-02-17]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[55]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[Sunday Business Post - The lay of the Pensions Landscape]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.iipm.ie/resources/files/Sunday%20Business%20Post%20interview%20with%20Rose%20Leonard,%20IIPM%20President.pdf">Click here&nbsp;t</a>o read the article in full</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2016-02-19]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title><![CDATA[Sunday Business Post - The lay of the Pensions Landscape]]></image_title>
    <metatitle><![CDATA[Sunday Business Post - The lay of the Pensions Landscape]]></metatitle>
    <metadescription><![CDATA[Sunday Business Post - The lay of the Pensions Landscape]]></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[57]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[Public "unaware" pension tax relief better than SSIA scheme]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>This article can be accessed by clicking on the following link:</p>



<p><a href="http://www.independent.ie/business/personal-finance/pensions/public-unaware-pension-tax-relief-better-than-ssia-scheme-34421525.html">http://www.independent.ie/business/personal-finance/pensions/public-unaware-pension-tax-relief-better-than-ssia-scheme-34421525.html</a></p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2016-02-23]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[media]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[59]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[The Pensions Authority Statement of Strategy 2016 - 2020]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>The Pensions Authority published its Statement of Strategy 2016 - 2020 setting out its vision, mission, values and the strategic objectives and high level strategies that will underpin its work programme for the next five years.&nbsp; Click on the following link to read the Authority&#39;s Statement of Strategy.</p>



<p><a href="http://www.pensionsauthority.ie/en/News_Press/News_Press_Archive/The_Pensions_Authority_Statement_of_Strategy_2016_-_2020.PDF">http://www.pensionsauthority.ie/en/News_Press/News_Press_Archive/The_Pensions_Authority_Statement_of_Strategy_2016_-_2020.PDF</a></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2016-03-04]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[61]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[Women, face up to your pensions]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>This article can be accessed by clicking on the following link:</p>



<p><a href="http://www.independent.ie/business/personal-finance/pensions/women-face-up-to-your-pensions-34574505.html">http://www.independent.ie/business/personal-finance/pensions/women-face-up-to-your-pensions-34574505.html</a></p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2016-03-30]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[media]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[63]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[Extension of ARF option announced]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">The Institute welcomes the statement by Minister Michael Noonan TD, that with effect from 22 June, holders of buyout bonds ( formally called &ldquo;approved policies&rdquo; and often referred to as Personal Retirement Bonds) will have access to the post-retirement investment option , Approved Retirement Funds (ARFs).&nbsp; Previously, these were accessible only to holders of Personal Retirement Savings Accounts, Certain Defined Contribution pension schemes, and holders of additional voluntary contributions (AVCs).</p>



<p style="text-align: justify;">The majority of those in buyout bonds were there through no desire of their own &ndash; most were purchased by the trustees of pension schemes in winding-up, though some were the result of Pension Adjustment Orders following separation or divorce.</p>



<p style="text-align: justify;">IIPM and its members have been campaigning for a number of years to have these bonds recognised as what they are &ndash; defined contribution pension arrangements.&nbsp; The legislation under which these bonds are approved has outlived its usefulness &nbsp;and we are pleased that the Minister has recognised the fairness of permitting access to ARFs for bond holders, particularly in the current climate of low interest rates, where compulsory annuity purchase makes no sense from either the State&rsquo;s or the bond-holders point of view.</p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2016-06-23]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[65]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[The Pensions Authority publishes Codes of Governance for Defined Contribution Schemes]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>The Pensions Authority has developed codes of governance for DC schemes which set out the standards trustees will be expected to adopt to demonstrate their commitment to serving the best interests of members and beneficiaries.</p>



<p>The Authority has published 9 codes so far in 2016 in three seperate tranches.&nbsp; You can access the codes by clicking on the following link:</p>



<p><a href="http://www.pensionsauthority.ie/en/Publications/Codes_of_governance_for_DC_schemes/">http://www.pensionsauthority.ie/en/Publications/Codes_of_governance_for_DC_schemes/</a></p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2016-06-23]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[67]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[The Real Issue Facing The Economy Is Demographics]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.businesspost.ie/pensions-summit-the-real-issue-facing-the-economy-is-demographics/">The Real Issue Facing The Economy Is Demographics&nbsp;</a></p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2016-09-20]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[68]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[Application for Fellowship Now Open!]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<div>

<p>All &quot;paid up&quot; <a href="page.php?id=15" title="Associate (AIIPM)">Associates (AIIPM)</a> of the Irish Institute of Pensions Management, who meet the required guidelines, are invited to apply for election to Fellowship of the Institute.</p>



<p>If, having read the guidelines, you feel you are eligible for consideration you should complete and sign an <a href="http://iipm.ie/resources/files/Fellowship%20Application%20Form%202016.pdf">Application Form</a> and forward the other forms for completion by the attestors.</p>



<p>All the relevant documentation is available for download below. All completed forms should be returned to reach the Secretary General of the Institute not later than 28th October 2016, and sent to the following address:</p>



<p style="margin-left: 40px">Irish Institute of Pensions Management<br />

National College of Ireland<br />

Mayor Street<br />

IFSC,Dublin 1</p>



<h3><strong>Subscriptions</strong></h3>



<p>The annual subscription of Fellow (FIIPM) is &euro;255.00.</p>



<p>See: <a href="http://iipm.ie/resources/files/Fellowship%20Attestor%20Form%202016.pdf">Fellowship Attestor Form</a> and <a href="http://iipm.ie/resources/files/Fellowship%20Guidelines%202016.pdf">Election Guidelines</a></p>

</div>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2016-10-05]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[70]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[How a bond bubble might sink Irish investors and pension savers]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.irishtimes.com/business/personal-finance/how-a-bond-bubble-might-sink-irish-investors-and-pension-savers-1.2804783">http://www.irishtimes.com/business/personal-finance/how-a-bond-bubble-might-sink-irish-investors-and-pension-savers-1.2804783</a></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2016-10-20]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[media]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[71]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[Our Ageing Population]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://iipm.ie/resources/files/Our%20Ageing%20Population.pdf">Our Ageing Population</a></p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2016-11-15]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[73]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[Honary Life Member]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>Paul Kenny was a founder Fellow of Irish Institute of Pensions Management and served as Pensions Ombudsman in Ireland from 2003 to 2016. He is the first and only Honorary Life Member of IIPM. Paul is pictured with his wife Ann receiving his Award from Rose Leonard, President of the IIPM.</p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2017-01-19]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image><![CDATA[Paul and Ann Kenny Dec 2016.jpg]]></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[75]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA["Death Bed Marriage" Rule in Pension Scheme Not Discriminatory]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>On 24 November 2016 the Court of Justice of the EU issued its judgement in the Dr David Parris v Trinity College Dublin case.&nbsp; Follow the link below to read the details.</p>



<p><a href="http://www.williamfry.com/newsandinsights/publications-article/2017/02/10/death-bed-marriage-rule-in-pension-scheme-not-discriminatory">http://www.williamfry.com/newsandinsights/publications-article/2017/02/10/death-bed-marriage-rule-in-pension-scheme-not-discriminatory</a></p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2017-02-13]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[77]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[Trustee Administrator Opportunity]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>Independent Trustee Limited have a role for a Trustee Administrator. We are looking for someone with good group pension knowledge and experience and ideally a pension qualification, such as the IIPM Diploma or Certificate. This is a full-time role. If you are interested please contact Elma Fox at <a href="mailto:elma.fox@trustee.ie">elma.fox@trustee.ie</a><br />

&nbsp;</p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2017-03-01]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[79]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[Diploma in Pensions Management & Policy - Enrolment Now Open!]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>Enrolment is now open for our Diploma in Pensions Management &amp; Policy commencing mid-September.</p>



<p>For Programme information, exemptions, etc please <a href="https://www.ncirl.ie/Courses/Course-Details?course=Diploma-in-Pensions-Management-%26-Policy---Online-DIPENMANO4">click here</a></p>



<p>Enquires also to <a href="mailto:iipm@ncirl.ie">iipm@ncirl.ie</a> / 01 4498512</p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2017-03-24]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[81]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[Fellowship Applications]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>We are inviting Associates who have held membership of IIPM at Associate level for more than 5 years to apply for election to Fellowship of IIPM. &nbsp;Applicants must be paid up in respect of subscriptions and must meet the criteria as set out in our Election Guidelines. The Election Guidelines together with the appropriate application form are attached above.</p>



<p>&nbsp;If you would like to be considered for Fellowship, please read the Election Guidelines carefully, complete the appropriate application form and arrange for the Attestor Forms to be completed on your behalf. &nbsp;All forms must be submitted to the following address by <strong><u>Wednesday, 25<sup>th</sup> October</u></strong> please.</p>



<p>Fellowship Awards will be presented at our annual dinner which will take place on Friday 10th November 2017 in Stephen&rsquo;s Green Hibernian Club.</p>



<p>More information and forms are availabe <a href="http://iipm.ie/cms_admin/pages/edit_pages.php?id=14">by clicking here</a></p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2017-10-11]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[83]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[First Graduates of QPT (IIPM) programme receiving their awards from Rose Leonard, Past President]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>Pictured receiving their Awards from IIPM Past President Rose Leonard were Mark O&#39;Sullivan (Aon), Richard O&#39;Neill (Zurich), Michael O&#39;Driscoll (FDC), Anthony Horgan (Irish Life) and Maurice Ryan (Zurich).<br />

<br />

&nbsp;</p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2017-10-25]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image><![CDATA[Rose Leonard with recent QPT Graduates.jpg]]></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[85]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[Key Function Holders - IIPM submission to The Pensions Authority]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://iipm.ie/resources/files/KFH%20consultation%20submission%20form%20-%20IIPM%20Final.pdf">&nbsp;Key Function Holders&nbsp; - IIPM submission to the Pensions Authority</a></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2018-01-31]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle><![CDATA[Key Function Holders - IIPM submission to The Pensions Authority]]></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[87]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[Job Opportunity - Membership Services Administrator]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p><strong>Membership Services Administrator</strong></p>



<p><strong>Fixed Term Contract, Full Time or Part Time Permanent Position</strong></p>



<p><strong>Salary Scale: Dependent on Experience </strong></p>



<p><strong>Closing Date for Applications: Tuesday 5<sup>th</sup> March</strong></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>The Company</strong></p>



<p>The Irish Association of Pension Funds (IAPF) is a non-profit membership organisation. On behalf of its members, the IAPF seeks to influence the future direction of pensions in Ireland to ensure people can have pensions that are secure, fair and simple. IAPF is also the leading organiser of pension conferences, seminars and training in Ireland. Please see our website for more information www.iapf.ie</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Description</strong></p>



<p>The IAPF currently has a requirement for Membership Services Administrator</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>The Position</strong></p>



<p>The IAPF will provide secretariat services to the IIPM (the Irish Institute of Pensions Management) and as such will require a Membership Services Administrator to fulfil this role. You will be responsible for providing all round administrative duties such as accounts invoicing, membership administration and event planning for, first and foremost, the IIPM but also for the IAPF.</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is an exciting role for someone who is enthusiastic and capable of working on their own initiative. The successful candidate will work directly with the Commercial Operations Manager to provide a seamless, reliable, professional and accurate service for the Associations.</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Main Responsibilities of the Accounts and Membership Services Administrator</strong></p>



<ul>

<li>Process membership data / CPD info on internal database and website with high attention to detail and accuracy</li>

<li>Processing payments and generating invoices, including accurate follow up</li>

<li>Delivering high quality, prompt and customer focused service to members on the telephone, in person and by email, ensuring that all information and communications are professionally presented and accurate</li>

<li>Outgoing telephone/email interaction with members in order to provide excellent customer service and promote engagement</li>

<li>Attendance at events including registration of members on arrival</li>

<li>Providing administrative support to the office</li>

<li>Assisting with the efficient operation of the business</li>

</ul>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>The Candidate</strong></p>



<p>The candidate appointed will be a suitably experienced person with strong organisational and administration experience. You will possess the ability to establish positive and productive relationships with Council and Committees, members and staff to deliver a high level of member satisfaction.</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Personal Qualities:</strong></p>



<ul>

<li>The ideal candidate will be an enthusiastic, versatile professional with experience of accounts and office administration.</li>

</ul>



<ul>

<li>Ability to project an image of efficiency and helpfulness both on the telephone and through personal contact. Take ownership of queries/issues, bringing them to a successful conclusion.</li>

<li>Efficient in work methods, focus, and the ability to prioritize and balance multiple projects and deal with competing requirements.</li>

</ul>



<ul>

<li>Demonstrate a high level of initiative, energy and motivation with a proven history of implementing process&nbsp;improvements.</li>

<li>A strong work ethic and a collegial spirit. Ability to work both as part of a team and on own initiative. Who has strong relationship building skills with an ability to establish trust and instil confidence in others</li>

<li>Mature, motivated with excellent customer service and interpersonal skills</li>

</ul>



<ul>

<li>Capability to communicate clearly and well at all levels (written, spoken, including handling telephone) and sound numeracy skills.</li>

</ul>



<ul>

<li>Open to feedback and adaptable to change</li>

</ul>



<ul>

<li>Able to work under pressure and able to maintain calm Candidates must have flexibility with regard to working hours. Travel and other associated expenses will be&nbsp;reimbursed.</li>

</ul>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Desired qualifications include:</strong></p>



<ul>

<li>A good knowledge of accounts administration, office administration, planning, budgeting, finance.</li>

<li>Experience with Sage 50 accounts package is desirable but not essential</li>

<li>Proficiency in Microsoft office Suite and standard office equipment;</li>

<li>Computer skills: Microsoft Office, Adobe Creative Suite, CMS, database savvy, email campaign applications (e.g., Mailchimp), Social Media platforms (e.g., Facebook, Twitter</li>

<li>Experience with Member relationship management</li>

<li>Event and project management experience</li>

<li>Able to attend occasional early morning and evening events and other off-site functions</li>

</ul>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Remuneration and Benefits</strong></p>



<ul>

<li>Salary Dependent on Experience</li>

<li>Excellent Working conditions</li>

<li>Training and Development opportunities</li>

<li>20 days annual leave</li>

<li>Contributary Pension</li>

<li>Death in service benefit</li>

</ul>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Application Procedure</strong></p>



<p>Applicants should forward a detailed CV together with a covering letter outlining why you think you are suitable for this role, in strict confidence to:</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>Deirdre Ross</p>



<p>Commercial Operations Manager, IAPF, Suite 2, Slane House, 25 Lower Mount Street, Dublin 2</p>



<p>Email: <a href="mailto:deirdre.ross@iapf.ie">deirdre.ross@iapf.ie</a> Ph: 016130870</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>A detailed job description is available on request. The IAPF is an equal opportunities employer.</p>



<p>Recruitment agencies please do not reply to this job advert.</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2019-02-25]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[no]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[88]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[Change isn't coming - it's already here - Ian Slattery, Irish Broker Magazine, August 2021]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>Change isn&#39;t coming - it&#39;s already here - Ian Slattery, Irish Broker Magazine, August 2021</p>



<p>Whilst there have been numerous delays, redrafts and U-turns, the changes we will see in the pension industry in the next 18 months will shape the landscape for the next generation. THE list of acronyms across our industry continues to grow: IORP II, SRD II, SFDR amongst others have entered the vocabulary in recent years. On the other hand, there are growing plans to remove some (EPPs, AMRFs, ARFs?) as the Irish pension industry is set to undergo seismic shifts in the years to come. The details of all these changes have been given ample airtime at the IIPM&rsquo;s own Webinars over the last year, along with plenty of articles from various industry players. Therefore, although they are beyond the scope of this article, please do get in touch if you would like to discuss further.</p>



<p><strong>Click&nbsp;the link below to read the full article:</strong></p>



<p><a href="https://www.iipm.ie/resources/files/Ian%20Slattery%20Irish%20Broker%20Mag%20Aug%202021.pdf">https://www.iipm.ie/resources/files/Ian%20Slattery%20Irish%20Broker%20Mag%20Aug%202021.pdf</a></p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2021-08-12]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[90]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[IIPM shortlisted for the Irish Pension Awards 2021]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>We are delighted to have been shortlisted for the Pensions Organisation of the Year award at the Irish Pension Awards 2021 in recognition of our updated educational programmes and for providing free CPD seminars to our members and industry colleagues throughout the pandemic. See the shortlist <a href="https://www.europeanpensions.net/irishawards/"><strong>here</strong></a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.europeanpensions.net/irishawards/"><img alt="" src="/resources/images/Irish%20Pension%20Awards%202021.png" style="height:153px; width:400px" /></a></p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2021-09-24]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[92]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[IIPM & Society of Actuaries Joint Webinar October 2021]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p><strong>Speakers:</strong></p>



<p>Ian Moynihan, Head of Client Services - Pension &amp; Risk, Irish Life</p>



<p><em><strong>Topic: Group DC Governance and IORP II</strong></em></p>



<p>Paul Torsney, Head of Trustee Services, Law Debenture Pension Trustees Ireland</p>



<p><em><strong>Topic: Governanace and reporting of climate change risk for pension schemes - the UK approach</strong></em></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>Click <a href="https://www.iipm.ie/resources/files/IIPM%20SoA%20Slides%20Oct-21.pdf"><strong>HERE </strong></a>for slides&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2021-11-04]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[94]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[IIPM wins at Irish Pension Awards 2021]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>We are delighted to have won the award for the Pensions Organisation of the Year at the Irish Pension Awards 2021 in recognition of the quality and relevance of our updated&nbsp; educational programmes,&nbsp;and for providing free CPD events for industry members on a broad range of topics.</p>



<p>To see our educational programmes, click&nbsp;<strong><a href="https://www.iipm.ie/page.php?id=3&amp;title=Courses">here</a></strong></p>



<p>To see our CPD event schedule, click <strong><a href="https://www.iipm.ie/page.php?id=6&amp;title=Events">here</a></strong></p>



<p>To see all the winners at the Irish Pension Awards 2021, click <strong><a href="https://www.europeanpensions.net/irishawards/winners21.php">here</a></strong></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2021-11-19]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image><![CDATA[Irish Pension Awards 2021.png]]></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[96]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[The Evolving Irish Pensions Landscape - IIPM & The Insurance Institute Webinar - October 2021]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p><strong>&quot;The Evolving Irish Pensions Landscape&quot;</strong></p>



<p><em>Presentation by IIPM President, Ian Slattery&nbsp;</em></p>



<p>IIPM &amp; The Insurance Institute Webinar - 28 October 2021</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>For the full presentation, see the link below</p>



<p><a href="https://www.iipm.ie/resources/files/ISY_IIPM_II_Slides_281021%20FINAL.pdf">https://www.iipm.ie/resources/files/ISY_IIPM_II_Slides_281021%20FINAL.pdf</a></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2021-11-25]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[98]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[IIPM December 2021 Webinar]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p><strong>George Nolan, Head of Retirement &amp; Technical Insights, New Ireland</strong><br />

<em>Topic:&nbsp; Pension Simplification</em><br />

<br />

<strong>Paul Ryan, Director, Paul Ryan Pension &amp; Financial Consultants Limited</strong><br />

<em>Topic: Implications of regulatory change on one man schemes</em></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>Slides from this webinar available <a href="https://www.iipm.ie/resources/files/IIPM%20December%202021.pdf"><strong>here</strong></a></p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2021-12-02]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[100]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[Invitation to apply for election to Fellowship]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>We are inviting Associates who have held membership of IIPM at Associate level for more than 5 years to apply for election to Fellowship of IIPM. &nbsp;</p>



<p>Applicants must be paid up in respect of subscriptions and must meet the criteria as set out in our Fellowship Application Guidelines.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.iipm.ie/resources/files/2021-2022%20Fellowship%20Application%20Pack.docx"><strong>Click here to download the application form and candidate guidelines.</strong></a></p>



<p>Fellowship Awards will be bestowed in February 2022.</p>



<p>If you would like to be considered for Fellowship, please read the Fellowship Application Guidelines carefully, complete the appropriate application form and arrange for the Attestor Forms to be completed on your behalf. &nbsp;</p>



<p>All application and attestor forms will be processed in line with our Data Privacy Notice which can be read <a href="https://iipm.ie/page.php?id=112&amp;title=Privacy-Policy">here</a>.</p>



<p>All forms must be submitted by email to <a href="mailto:info@iipm.ie">info@iipm.ie</a> by 14 January 2022.</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Ian Slattery</strong></p>



<p><strong>President, IIPM</strong></p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2021-12-03]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[102]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[IIPM March 2022 Webinar]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p><em><strong>&lsquo;ESG in DC: The Implications for trustees, advisors, and members&rsquo;</strong></em><br />

<br />

<strong>Speaker</strong>: Oliver Kelly, LCP Ireland<br />

<strong>Speaker</strong>: Joe Mottley, Clarus Investment Solutions</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>Slides available <a href="https://www.iipm.ie/resources/files/IIPM%20March%202022%20Webinar.pdf">here</a>:</p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2022-03-16]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[104]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[IIPM April 2022 Webinar]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p><strong>Topic: &#39;International Pension&nbsp;Transfers&#39;</strong></p>



<p>Speaker:&nbsp; &nbsp;<strong>Eoin Hassett, Business Development Manager, Independent Trustee Company Limited</strong></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>Slides available <a href="https://www.iipm.ie/resources/files/IIPM%20April%20Webinar%20Slides%20FINAL.pdf">here</a></p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2022-04-20]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[106]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[Forward thinking is key to a happy retirement - Sunday Business Post - 10 April 2022]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-size:14px"><strong>Forward thinking is key to a happy retirement - Sunday Business Post - 10 April 2022</strong></span></p>



<p>Proposed auto-enrolment scheme looks like the best chance to coax more people into the safety net of saving properly to ensure a more comfortable income in their golden years, say pensions experts</p>



<p>Full article <a href="https://www.iipm.ie/resources/files/Forward%20thinking%20is%20key%20to%20a%20happy%20retirement.pdf">here</a></p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2022-04-20]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[108]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[IIPM May 2022 Webinar]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p><br />

<em><strong>&#39;Practical Data Governance and an Update from the Data Protection Commission&#39;</strong></em><br />

<br />

Speaker: Colum Walsh, Deputy Commissioner, Data Protection Commission<br />

Speaker: Daragh O&#39;Brien, CEO, Castlebridge<br />

<br />

Slides from the webinar are available <a href="https://www.iipm.ie/resources/files/IIPM%20May%20Webinar%20Data%20Protection%20Update.pdf" target="_blank">here</a></p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2022-05-26]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[110]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[IIPM Salary Survey 2022 | Irish Independent Business]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p><strong>IIPM Salary Survey 2022 |&nbsp;Irish Independent Business | 7 July 2022</strong></p>



<p><img alt="" src="/resources/images/Irish Independent 07_07_2022.png" style="height:407px; width:498px" /></p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2022-07-28]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[112]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[IIPM Summer Update | July 2022]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<table align="center" border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0">

<tbody>

<tr>

<td>

<table border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" style="width:100.0%">

<tbody>

<tr>

<td>&nbsp;</td>

</tr>

</tbody>

</table>



<table border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" style="width:100.0%">

<tbody>

<tr>

<td>

<table align="left" border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" style="width:100.0%">

<tbody>

<tr>

<td style="width:600px">

<table align="left" border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" style="width:100.0%">

<tbody>

<tr>

<td>

<p><strong>IIPM delighted to host first in person seminar since 2019</strong><br />

<br />

The Irish Institute of Pensions Management was delighted to host our first in person seminar since 2019 on 23rd June in Chartered Accountants Ireland House, kindly sponsored by Irish Life.&nbsp; Along with our formal education courses offered in conjunction with Griffith College Dublin, our CPD events&nbsp; are an integral part of our membership benefits package.&nbsp; They offer a clear opportunity to hear directly from industry practitioners and regulators, and for them to hear directly from us.&nbsp; It was great to be back in person and to chat with our Members, Associates, Fellows and guests, to discuss the topics as they unfolded.<br />

<br />

Many thanks to Clare Dowling from the DSP and Brendan Kennedy from The Pensions Authority for their contributions.&nbsp; The industry continues to undergo rapid change, as deadlines (including in the last week) come thick and fast.&nbsp; The decisions being made in 2022 will reverberate throughout the industry for decades to come.&nbsp; There is seldom (or perhaps never!) universal agreement in relation to the topics at hand, but the IIPM firmly&nbsp; believe that constructive debate and dialogue is the best route forward.&nbsp; We are looking forward to our next events in partnership with the Association of Pension Lawyers in Ireland and Society of Actuaries in Ireland over the comings months - further details&nbsp;<a href="https://iipm.us17.list-manage.com/track/click?u=9d7a3c37c74aa6249fa99a785&amp;id=eb85e29b35&amp;e=13b67d60c2" target="_blank"><strong>here</strong></a>.<br />

<br />

<strong>Higher Diploma Course information session announced</strong><br />

<br />

The IIPM are hosting an information session for prospective Higher Diploma students on Tuesday 9th August 09:00 to 09:30.&nbsp; The webinar will be conducted by Alan Brooks, Programme Director, and Ian Slattery from the IIPM&#39;s perspective.&nbsp;The session will cover:</p>



<ul>

<li>Course content</li>

<li>Benefits of undertaking the course</li>

<li>Registration and exemptions process</li>

<li>Practical next steps for prospective students</li>

<li>Followed by a Q&amp;A session</li>

</ul>



<p><br />

The session will finish promptly at 09:30.&nbsp; Interested students can register for the Zoom webinar <a href="https://iipm.us17.list-manage.com/track/click?u=9d7a3c37c74aa6249fa99a785&amp;id=89929f0ae8&amp;e=13b67d60c2" target="_blank"><strong>HERE&nbsp;</strong></a>OR by <strong><a href="mailto:info@iipm.ie?subject=Course%20Information%20Session%20-%209th%20August">reply to this email</a>,</strong>&nbsp;and the link will follow in due course. We would appreciate if you could share the link as appropriate with interested parties from both within and outside your organisation.&nbsp; Any help is much appreciated.<br />

<br />

Course information for Employers can be found&nbsp;<a href="https://iipm.us17.list-manage.com/track/click?u=9d7a3c37c74aa6249fa99a785&amp;id=88d342a261&amp;e=13b67d60c2" target="_blank"><strong>here</strong></a><br />

<br />

<strong>PMI Pinnacle Awards 2022</strong><br />

<br />

The Pensions Management Institute in the UK are hosting the <a href="https://iipm.us17.list-manage.com/track/click?u=9d7a3c37c74aa6249fa99a785&amp;id=34ff6e5bc8&amp;e=13b67d60c2" target="_blank">PMI Pinnacle Awards</a> once again in 2022.&nbsp; The PMI Pinnace Awards recognise&nbsp; the best of the pensions profession and aims to celebrate people and new ideas that contribute in making a real impact in the pensions world.&nbsp; The deadline for entries is 9th July.<br />

<br />

If you have any queries regarding these awards, please contact Francesca Levy-Garrett, Executive Support Manager, at <a href="mailto:FSchiller@pensions-pmi.org.uk" target="_blank">FSchiller@pensions-pmi.org.uk </a>or Varsha Gicas, Director of Commerce and Engagement, at <a href="mailto:VGicas@pensions-pmi.org.uk" target="_blank">VGicas@pensions-pmi.org.uk</a>. The telephone number of the Institute is +44 20 7247 1452.<br />

&nbsp;</p>

</td>

</tr>

</tbody>

</table>

</td>

</tr>

</tbody>

</table>

</td>

</tr>

</tbody>

</table>

</td>

</tr>

</tbody>

</table>



<div style="clear:both;">&nbsp;</div>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2022-07-28]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[114]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[IIPM June 2022 Seminar]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p><em><strong>&#39;Pensions Reform and Pensions Authority Update&#39;</strong></em><br />

<br />

Speaker: <strong>Brendan Kennedy, Pensions Regulator, The Pensions Authority</strong><br />

Speaker: <strong>Clare Dowling, Principal Officer, Auto-enrolment Programme Management Office, Dept of Social Protection</strong><br />

<br />

Slides from the webinar are available <a href="https://www.iipm.ie/resources/files/Clare%20Dowling%20-%20Auto%20Enrolment%20-%20IIPM%20June%202022.pdf" target="_blank">here</a></p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2022-07-28]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[115]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[IIPM March 2023 Webinar]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p><strong>Topic:&nbsp; Investments</strong></p>



<p>Speakers:</p>



<p><strong>Mike Bell of JP Morgan and Dominic Byrne of Blackrock</strong></p>



<p><em>In keeping with our trend in recent years, the IIPM are delighted to kick off our 2023 CPD Programme with a focus on Investments. IIPM President, Ian Slattery, will be joined by Mike Bell of JP Morgan and Dominic Byrne of Blackrock. 2022 was a poor year for DC investors as both equities and bonds suffered large losses. Whilst falling bond prices helped the funding levels of DB schemes,&nbsp; it was not all plain sailing in a year dominated by inflation. Mike and Dominic will unpack many of the key issues faced by pension investors and also outline some of the practical actions scheme trustees and advisors can take to help keep their member&rsquo;s retirement funding plans on track.</em></p>



<p><strong>Slides </strong>from the webinar are available <a href="https://www.iipm.ie/resources/files/IIPM%20March%20Webinar%20Slides.pdf">here</a></p>



<p><strong>Delegate handouts</strong> available to download <a href="https://www.iipm.ie/resources/files/JPMAM%20Q1%2023-guide-to-the-markets.pdf">here </a>and <a href="https://www.iipm.ie/resources/files/JPMAM%20Q4%2022-guide-to-alternatives.pdf">here</a></p>



<p><strong>Webinar recording</strong>:&nbsp;<a href="https://attendee.gotowebinar.com/recording/336514759438563926">https://attendee.gotowebinar.com/recording/336514759438563926</a></p>



<p><strong>CPD</strong>: 2 hours in category: Savings &amp; Investments, LIA15727_2023, IOB 2023-0767</p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2023-03-10]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[117]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[Business Post - Pensions Report 2023]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<h1><strong><span style="font-size:18px">Business Post - Pensions Report 2023</span></strong></h1>



<p>7 April 2023</p>



<h1>PRSI rise of around &euro;1,800 a year needed to fund pensions</h1>



<p>The number of people aged over 65, compared to those aged 15 to 64, is set to more than double from 22 per cent in 2020 to 47 per cent in 2050 &ndash; and we need to prepare for that now, says a financial and pensions expert</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>Read the full article <span style="font-size:14px"><strong><a href="https://www.businesspost.ie/article/prsi-rise-of-around-e1800-a-year-needed-to-fund-pensions/">here</a></strong></span>:&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2023-04-07]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[119]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[IIPM April 2023 Webinar]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p><strong>Topic:&nbsp; Auto Enrolment</strong></p>



<p>Speaker:</p>



<p><strong>Shane O&#39;Farrell, Director of Sales, Irish Life Corporate Business</strong></p>



<p><em>Auto-Enrolment looks sets to be the most pivotal policy change in the Irish pensions landscape over the coming years, and is due to have a profound impact on retirement savings for those in the private workforce. <strong>Shane O&rsquo;Farrell</strong>, Director of Sales at Irish Life Corporate Business as Shane gives his view on the proposals</em>.</p>



<p><strong>Slides </strong>from the webinar are available <a href="https://www.iipm.ie/resources/files/IIPM%20April%20Webinar%20Slides%20FINAL_0.pdf">here</a></p>



<p><strong>Webinar recording</strong>:&nbsp;<a href="https://attendee.gotowebinar.com/recording/8425079746682842288">https://attendee.gotowebinar.com/recording/8425079746682842288</a></p>



<p><strong>CPD</strong>: 1&nbsp;hour&nbsp;in category: Pensions, LIA15892_2023, IOB 2023-1521</p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2023-04-21]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[121]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[IIPM & APLI May 2023 Webinar]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p><strong>Topic:&nbsp; Master Trusts Transition - A trustee update</strong></p>



<p><em>During a period of intense activity and decision making for employers, trustees, providers and their advisors, we are checking in with the key stakeholders on how their transition (or not) to Master Trust is going.</em></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>Chaired by:</p>



<p><strong>Davin Spollen, IIPM President</strong></p>



<p><strong>Orla Ormsby,&nbsp;Commercial and Pensions Counsel, Head of Legal &ndash; Intermediary Division/Irish Life Group</strong></p>



<p>Speakers:</p>



<p><strong>Philip Smith, Partner, Arthur Cox</strong></p>



<p><strong>Barry Grennan, Business Centre Manager, Xerox Europe Ltd</strong></p>



<p><strong>Martin Dobey, Chairman, Staff Pension Trustees, KPMG</strong></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>Slides from the webinar are available <strong><a href="https://www.iipm.ie/resources/files/IIPM%20May%20Webinar%20-%20Delegate%20Slides.pdf">here</a></strong></p>



<p>Webinar recording <strong><a href="https://attendee.gotowebinar.com/recording/4420382421677541805">here</a></strong></p>



<p><strong>CPD</strong></p>



<p>2 hours Pensions |&nbsp;LIA16035_2023 | IOB 2023-1904</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2023-05-26]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[122]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[IIPM June 2023 Seminar]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>Chaired by:</p>



<p><strong>Davin Spollen, IIPM President</strong></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Speakers</strong>:</p>



<p>Suzanne Whelan | Programmes Director | Pensions Programme | Griffith College</p>



<p><em><strong>Regulatory Update </strong></em>- Grace Guy | Head of Supervision and Enforcement | Pensions Authority</p>



<p><em><strong>Overview of Pension Fund Developments</strong></em> - Kenneth Devine | Senior Economist-Stastician | Head of Insurance Corporation &amp; Pension Fund Statistics | Central Bank of Ireland</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>Slides from the webinar are available <a href="https://www.iipm.ie/resources/files/IIPM%20June%20Seminar%20SLIDES.pdf">here</a></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>CPD</strong></p>



<p>2 hours Pensions |&nbsp;LIA16157_2023 | IOB 2023-2084</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2023-06-21]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[124]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[IIPM December 2023 Seminar]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>Chaired by:</p>



<p><strong>Davin Spollen, IIPM President</strong></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Speakers</strong>:</p>



<p>Eoin Hassett | Director Trustee Services |&nbsp;Independent Trustee Limited</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Topic:</strong></p>



<p>&#39;<em>Maintaining Ethical Behaviour During Times of Change&#39;</em></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>Slides from the webinar are available <a href="https://www.iipm.ie/resources/files/IIPM%20Ethics%202023%20EH%20Slides.pdf">here</a></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>CPD</strong></p>



<p>1 hour Ethics |&nbsp;LIA01164_2023 | IOB Pending</p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2023-12-08]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[126]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[IIPM November 2023 Webinar]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>GROUP PROTECTION UPDATE</strong></p>



<p>Speakers and Topics:</p>



<p><em>&#39;<strong>Building the Income Protection Plan of the Future &ndash; Benefit Philosophy, Design, Sustainability&#39;</strong></em></p>



<p><strong>Marian Conway, Senior Manager &ndash; Group Protection Proposition, Irish Life Corporate Business</strong></p>



<p>and</p>



<p><strong><em>&#39;Death in Service Benefits &ndash; Origins, Evolution and Future in the world of Master Trusts&#39;</em></strong></p>



<p><strong>Brian Hosford, Propositions Manager &ndash; Group Protection, Aviva Life &amp; Pensions Ireland</strong></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>SLIDES</strong></p>



<p>Slides from the webinar are available&nbsp;<a href="https://www.iipm.ie/resources/files/IIPM%20November%20FINAL%20SLIDES.pdf">here</a></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>RECORDING</strong></p>



<p>Available to view <a href="https://attendee.gotowebinar.com/recording/7731562791953382744">here</a></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>CPD</strong></p>



<p>2 hours Pensions |&nbsp;LIA16720_2023 | IOB 2023-3249</p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2023-11-09]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[128]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[IIPM March 2024 Seminar]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>INVESTMENT WEBINAR</strong></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>Speakers and Topics:</p>



<p><em>&#39;&#39;</em><strong><em>New World Disorder &ndash; Navigating the Return of History and Rising Multi-Dimensional Volatility&#39;</em></strong></p>



<p><strong>Alexander Chartres, Fund Manager, Ruffer</strong></p>



<p>and</p>



<p><strong><em>&#39;From the Macro to the Micro&#39;</em></strong></p>



<p><strong>Ian Slattery, Head of Investment - Zurich Life, IIPM Vice President</strong></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>SLIDES</strong></p>



<p>Slides from the webinar are available&nbsp;<a href="https://www.iipm.ie/resources/files/NWD%202024%20-%20Ireland%20-%20FINAL.pdf">here</a></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>RECORDING</strong></p>



<p>Available to view <a href="https://attendee.gotowebinar.com/recording/4486551038096114179">here</a></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>CPD</strong></p>



<p>1 hour Savings &amp; Investment |&nbsp;LIA01893_2024 | IOB 2024-1166 | FPSB 1 CPD hour</p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2024-03-28]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[130]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[IIPM April 2024 Webinar]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>AUTO ENROLMENT</strong></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>Speakers:</p>



<p><strong>Stephen Lalor - Pensions Consultant</strong></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>SLIDES</strong></p>



<p>Slides from the webinar are available&nbsp;<a href="https://www.iipm.ie/resources/files/Auto%20Enrolment%20April%202024%20with%20Q&amp;A_25.04.2024_0.pptx">here</a>&nbsp;<em>(automatically Downloads)</em></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>RECORDING</strong></p>



<p>Available to view <a href="https://attendee.gotowebinar.com/recording/4454709181974334212">here</a></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>CPD</strong></p>



<p>1 hours Pensions |&nbsp;LIA01954_2024 | IOB 2024-1367</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2024-04-19]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[132]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[IIPM May 2024 Webinar]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>AUTO ENROLMENT - PART II</strong></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>Speaker:</p>



<p><strong>Stephen Lalor - Pensions Consultant</strong></p>



<p>Panel:</p>



<p><strong>Tim Duggan, Assistant Secretary General, Department of Social Protection</strong></p>



<p><strong>Kevin Cruise O&rsquo;Shea, IAPF Chairperson and Head of Compensation and Benefits, Musgrave Group</strong></p>



<p><strong>Orla Ormsby, Head of Legal for the Intermediary Division and Pensions Counsel at Irish Life</strong></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>SLIDES</strong></p>



<p>Slides from the webinar are available&nbsp;<a href="https://www.iipm.ie/resources/files/Auto%20Enrolment%20May%202024%20v2.pdf">here</a>&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>RECORDING</strong></p>



<p>Available to view <a href="https://attendee.gotowebinar.com/recording/8528238135448583852">here</a></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>CPD</strong></p>



<p>2 hours Pensions |&nbsp;LIA17320_2024 | IOB 2024-1761</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2024-05-24]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[134]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[IIPM June 2024 Seminar]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>In Person Seminar only</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>REGULATORY UPDATE</strong></p>



<p>Speaker:</p>



<p><strong>Brendan Kennedy, Pensions Regulator, the Pensions Authority</strong></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>IRISH MASTER TRUST SURVEY 2024</strong></p>



<p>Speaker:</p>



<p><strong>Martin Haugh, Partner, LCP Ireland</strong></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>SLIDES</strong></p>



<p>Link to LCP Master Trusts Survey 2024 slides <a href="https://www.iipm.ie/resources/files/LCP%20Ireland%20Master%20Trust%20Survey%202024.pdf"><span style="font-size:14px"><strong>here</strong></span></a></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>CPD</strong></p>



<p>1 hours Pensions |&nbsp;LIA17401_2024 | IOB 2024-1775</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2024-06-12]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[136]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[IIPM September 2024 Webinar]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><span style="font-size:18px"><strong>IIPM SEPTEMBER 2024 WEBINAR - ETHICS</strong></span></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>Speakers:</p>



<p><strong>Nadina Stodiek</strong><strong> | Co-head of Impact Management | Schroeders</strong><br />

Impact Investing<br />

<br />

<strong>Brian Macdonald | Managing Director | Trustee Decisions</strong><br />

Ethics and Pension Scheme Trustees</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>SLIDES</strong></p>



<p>Slides from the webinar are available&nbsp;<a href="https://www.iipm.ie/resources/files/Auto%20Enrolment%20May%202024%20v2.pdf">here</a><a href="https://www.iipm.ie/resources/files/IIPM%20September%202024%20Webinar%20FINAL.pdf">&nbsp;</a></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>RECORDING</strong></p>



<p>Available to view <a href="https://attendee.gotowebinar.com/recording/2818844790458448130">here</a></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>CPD</strong></p>



<p>1 hour in categories:&nbsp;Pensions |&nbsp;Savings &amp; Investment |&nbsp;Ethics&nbsp;|&nbsp;LIA17706_2024 | IOB 2024-2631</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2024-10-09]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[138]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[IIPM & SAI October  2024 Webinar]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p><strong>IIPM &amp; SAI OCTOBER 2024 WEBINAR</strong></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>CHAIRS:</strong><br />

<strong>Davin Spollen | IIPM President | Glennon</strong><br />

<strong>Tom Matthews |&nbsp;Chair of Pensions Committee | Society of Actuaries in Ireland</strong></p>



<p><strong>SPEAKERS &amp; TOPICS:</strong><br />

<strong>Jim Power | Economist</strong><br />

<em>Ireland&rsquo;s Economic Outlook, post-Budget</em><br />

<strong>Tony Gilhawley | Pensions Consultant | Fellow of the Society of Actuaries in Ireland</strong><br />

<em>Update on State Pension Deferral option and the&nbsp;Standard Fund Threshold</em></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>SLIDES</strong></p>



<p>Slides from the webinar are available&nbsp;<a href="https://www.iipm.ie/resources/files/Slides%2024%20Oct%202024%20FINAL.pdf">here</a><a href="https://www.iipm.ie/resources/files/IIPM%20September%202024%20Webinar%20FINAL.pdf">&nbsp;</a></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>RECORDING</strong></p>



<p>Available to view <a href="https://attendee.gotowebinar.com/recording/4636271541248670038">here</a></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>CPD</strong></p>



<p>2 hours in categories:&nbsp;Pensions&nbsp;|&nbsp;LIA17888_2024 | IOB 2024-3271 | FPSB 2 hours</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2024-10-25]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[139]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[IIPM November 2024 Webinar]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>IIPM NOVEMBER&nbsp;2024 WEBINAR</strong></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>TOPIC: GROUP PROTECTION</strong></p>



<p>Multi-National Business &ndash; Pooling &amp; Captive Arrangements in the Modern International Employee Benefits Market</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>SPEAKERS:</strong></p>



<p>Bahareh Zamani, IGP Europe</p>



<p>David Schupak, Global Director,&nbsp;Relationship Management at MAXIS GBN, London</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>SLIDES</strong></p>



<p>Slides from the webinar are available&nbsp;<a href="https://www.iipm.ie/resources/files/IIPM%20Webinar%207%20Nov%202024.pdf">here</a><a href="https://www.iipm.ie/resources/files/IIPM%20September%202024%20Webinar%20FINAL.pdf">&nbsp;</a></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>RECORDING</strong></p>



<p>Available to view <a href="https://attendee.gotowebinar.com/recording/2274535958259118767">here</a></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>CPD</strong></p>



<p>2 hours in categories:&nbsp;Life Assurance |&nbsp;LIA17938_2024 | IOB 2024-3351 | FPSB n/a</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2024-11-12]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[140]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[IIPM December 2024 Seminar]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p><strong>IIPM DECEMBER 2024 SEMINAR</strong></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>TOPIC:&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>Retirement Planning vs Planning for Retirement</p>



<p><strong>SPEAKER:</strong></p>



<p>Declan Lawlor | Retirement Planning Council of Ireland</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>TOPIC:&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>Advice at the Point of Retirement and Beyond</p>



<p><strong>SPEAKER:</strong></p>



<p>Jonathan Kerr | IIPM Council | WTW</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>SLIDES</strong></p>



<p>Slides from the webinar are available&nbsp;<a href="https://www.iipm.ie/resources/files/IIPM%20December%20Final%202024%20Slides.pdf">here</a><a href="https://www.iipm.ie/resources/files/IIPM%20September%202024%20Webinar%20FINAL.pdf">&nbsp;</a></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>RECORDING</strong></p>



<p>In Person only - Not recorded</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>CPD</strong></p>



<p>2 hours in category Pensions: IIPM</p>



<p>1 hour in category Pensions |&nbsp;LIA18207_2024| IOB 2024-3791 | FPSB n/a</p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2024-12-12]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[142]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[IIPM February 2025 Webinar]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p><strong>IIPM FEBRUARY 2025 WEBINAR</strong></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>TOPIC:&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>Current Investment Outlook for the Investment Markets</p>



<p><strong>SPEAKERS:</strong></p>



<p>Lenny McLoughlin |&nbsp;Irish Life Investment Managers</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>TOPIC:&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>&#39;Staying invested: the 7 investment lessons&rsquo; &amp;<br />

&lsquo;Diversification: why it matters in a multi-asset portfolio&rsquo;</p>



<p><strong>SPEAKERS:</strong></p>



<p>Peter Smith | Aviva Investors</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>SLIDES</strong></p>



<p>Slides from the webinar are available&nbsp;<a href="https://www.iipm.ie/resources/files/IIPM%20February%202025%20FINAL%20SLIDES.pdf">here</a><a href="https://www.iipm.ie/resources/files/IIPM%20September%202024%20Webinar%20FINAL.pdf">&nbsp;</a></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>RECORDING</strong></p>



<p>Available to view&nbsp;<a href="https://attendee.gotowebinar.com/recording/4109621966696570975">here</a></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>CPD</strong></p>



<p>2 hours in categories:&nbsp;Pensions &amp; Savings &amp; Investment |&nbsp;LIA18419_2025 | IOB 2025-0800 | 2 hours FPSB</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2025-02-13]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id><![CDATA[144]]></id>
    <title><![CDATA[IIPM March 2025 Webinar]]></title>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>IIPM MARCH 2025 WEBINAR</strong></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>TOPIC:&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>DORA</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>SPEAKERS:</strong></p>



<p>John Harney | Associate Partner and Pensions Cyber Risk Governance expert | AON&nbsp;<br />

David Burwell | Head of EMEA Pensions Cyber Risk Governance | AON</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>SLIDES</strong></p>



<p>Slides from the webinar are available&nbsp;<a href="https://www.iipm.ie/resources/files/IIPM%20Final%20Slides%20March%202025.pdf">here</a><a href="https://www.iipm.ie/resources/files/IIPM%20September%202024%20Webinar%20FINAL.pdf">&nbsp;</a></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>RECORDING</strong></p>



<p>Available to view&nbsp;<a href="https://attendee.gotowebinar.com/recording/7318867710530262955">here</a></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>CPD</strong></p>



<p>1 hour | Category:&nbsp;Pensions |&nbsp;LIA not applicable | IOB 2025-0732 | FPSB TBC</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>

]]></content>
    <date_added><![CDATA[2025-03-20]]></date_added>
    <publish><![CDATA[yes]]></publish>
    <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
    <image></image>
    <image_title></image_title>
    <metatitle></metatitle>
    <metadescription></metadescription>
    <metakeywords></metakeywords>
  </item>
</wpiedata>
